[dramatic music playing]
[tires squealing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[cackling]
[tires squealing]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[gasps]
When is a pineapple not a pineapple?
When it's a grenade!
[laughing]
[gasping]
[straining]
-[tires squeal]
-[police sirens blaring]
Now. it's a party!
[cackling]
[suspenseful music continues]
[groans]
[man in green cackling]
[grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[fighting grunts and groans]
[Flass] Grenade!
[tires squealing]
We are losing this fight.
Not a fight anymore. boss.
This new guy is making it a war.
[theme music playing]
[Montoya] Where the hell is Thorne?
Detective. this will be a lot smoother
if you’d just make my client an offer.
Scare tactics won’t get you
where you want to go.
This guy.
[mysterious music playing]
Name.
He's running things. right?
Workin' for Thorne?
Or did he take over?
-Still not hearing an offer.
-Your guy tried to murder a witness!
Allegedly. detective. Allegedly.
He destroyed over a million dollars
worth of property.
I’m saying he doesn’t get an offer.
Suits me.
'Cause even if you made one.
I wouldn't take it.
Okay. Looks like we're done here.
-Whose side are you on. Gordon?
-The law’s side. Detective Flass.
You know. the thing you’re supposed
to protect and serve.
I'm no rat.
You of all people should know that.
-[grunts]
-You little piece of shit!
-What the hell? Renee!
-Hey! Ease up. Flass. Jesus!
Guard!
Hey. Flass.
Next time you talk to Mr. Thorne.
tell him to buy you a new suit.
[car horns honking]
[Gordon] I’m so sorry for your loss.
Mrs. Fuller.
Let me know if your family needs anything.
This department needed Fuller.
He was an honest officer.
and I don’t have many of those.
This one's the real question mark.
He started popping up
after Thorne’s arrest.
Since then. gangland murders
are triple what they were last year.
there have been two bombings.
and we only barely interrupted
a kidnapping this week.
One of Thorne’s lieutenants
making his own moves.
Could be. or Thorne’s finally lost it.
and this is his revenge on the city
for putting him on trial.
The one guy who might know
for sure isn’t talking.
[Batman] Mark Desmond.
Since Thorne’s trial.
Desmond’s the only member of the gang
we’ve brought in alive.
And he’d rather spend the next twenty
in Blackgate than be known as a snitch.
[Batman] He needs someone to confide in.
Someone he can trust.
That leaves out just about everyone
in Gotham. Unless you have a--
-[sighs]
-[jazz music playing]
[jazz music continues]
The son of a bitch is gonna
get us all killed.
He let Rocco get gunned down like a dog!
I don’t like Eddie anymore than you do.
but Mr. Thorne left him in charge.
If we go against Eddie.
we go against Mr. Thorne.
-And we owe him better than that.
-And where the hell is Mr. Thorne?
Coney Island. Timbuktu. it don’t matter!
Eddie’s in charge. The end.
[henchman] I'm telling you.
we need new leadership.
You got trouble. baby.
The tie?
You’re the one who picked it.
Not the tie!
Rocco getting killed ain’t sitting right
with the gang.
Ah. damn whiners!
They’re getting a bigger share
of the take. ain’t they?
Yeah. but Eddie. if Mr. Thorne
doesn’t come back soon--
What? Think I can't handle it?
No baby. never.
I’m just worried is all. About you.
But maybe talk with the boys now? For me?
Just so I don’t worry.
Hey. boys.
I understand there have been
some complaints.
Tony? Vic?
[clears throat] Uh. yeah. We. uh...
some of us got. you know. concerns.
You do. huh?
Well. let’s hear ‘em.
These jobs we been pullin’.
they pay out good.
nobody’s saying they don’t. but...
-they’re risky.
-No risk. no reward. Am I right?
Maybe they're a little too risky.
you know?
Like. maybe if we wasn’t
bracing the cops so much.
Rocco wouldn’t be dead.
Could be worse.
He could be in some cell.
getting worked over by cops
‘til he spills like a broken milk bottle.
Rocco was no rat!
Anybody's a rat.
you put on the right screws!
It’s like sitting in a leaky boat.
But you know how to fix a leaky boat.
Vicky boy?
How's that?
-[gunshot]
-[gasping. groaning]
-[body thudding]
-Now...
Anybody else got... concerns?
Speakin' of leaks.
I hear the badges have been visiting
my old buddy Dez at Blackgate.
I’m gonna need to put a plug in that too.
[tense music playing]
-[projector whirring]
-[classical music playing]
[man. over projector]
This thing's goin' south. Johnny.
[man #2. over projector]
Nah. We’re getting clear of this. see.
Even if we gotta drop
a couple coppers on the way.
[gunshots]
The boss don’t like us mixing it up
with the police. Johnny!
To hell with the boss.
He’d been holding back our cut.
I’m gonna take my due and give him his.
-[rattling]
[Pennyworth] The paperwork is ready.
Your transfer from stately Wayne Manor
to Blackgate Prison
will take place in an hour.
I trust that the legend I prepared for you
was satisfactory.
Master Bruce?
[dramatic music playing]
Where are you from?
Detroit.
Rap sheet?
Robbery. Fraud. Larceny.
Looking for a situation
driving for the mob.
[dramatic music continues]
[cell door unlocks. slides open]
The hell is this?
[guard] New roommate for ya. Dez.
Name's Matches.
Matches Malone.
Ah. who cares?
[low chatter]
Get used to it.
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[growls]
[fighting grunts and groans]
-[pants]
-What the hell happened here?
He scuffed my shoes.
[chuckles]
He scuffed your-- get 'em outta here!
[cell doors sliding closed]
-[faucet running]
-"He scuffed my shoes."
[chuckles] Brother. you are a caution.
Yeah. what can I say? I like a good shine.
Name's Dez.
You said. "Matches." before?
Yeah. Matches Malone.
Sorry if I was a jerk last night.
[dramatic music playing]
Forget about it.
[dramatic music continues]
[grunts] I feel like you and me met
before. sometime. On the outside.
Not likely. I'm new in town.
And already in Blackgate?
Brother. you know how to find trouble.
[tense music playing]
Better than trouble lookin' for me.
What?
Maybe we oughta drift.
Right behind ya.
[tense music continues]
Nice. You got a head on you.
Matches Malone.
[Matches] Hey. I’m not taking any bruises
I don’t buy.
Brother. I sure got lucky
getting you for a cellie.
-Let me tell ya.
-Me. not so much.
Who put the target on your back?
What target?
Two times some guys zeroed in on you.
You're marked.
[chuckles]
Sure. if they got a screw loose.
Anybody messes with me.
they answer to my boss.
-And he runs Gotham.
-Hey. maybe I did get lucky.
I came to Gotham looking for a situation
with whoever runs this burg.
Yeah? Okay.
Well. maybe we can talk about... that.
[suspenseful music playing]
[fighting grunts and groans]
[alarm ringing]
[dramatic music playing]
Get these clowns back to their cell.
[prisoners whimpering]
It don't make sense. These mooks know
better than to put hands on me.
I’m protected.
-By Rupert Thorne.
-Sure. sure. Wait. You heard of him?
Everyone in Detroit has heard of Thorne.
If that’s your boss. you wanna reach out.
-Let him know what’s going on in here.
-It’s Mister Thorne.
And you don’t reach out to Mister Thorne.
He reaches out to you.
Well. somebody better do something.
Sooner or later. whoever’s out to nail you
is gonna get lucky too.
[Beckett] Quiet in there!
Lights out!
[lights turning off]
[jazz music playing]
Drink up. baby. We got two bottles
of Silver Lining right here.
Oh. damn. here comes a rain cloud.
Better be good.
-This bubbly goes flat. and I will--
-[whispering]
Not... dead?
How the hell is he not dead?
It's almost a week since the hit went out!
What can I say. boss? He made a friend.
-[screaming]
-Friend?
-[grunting]
-Dez doesn't have friends!
-He's got... me!
-[groaning]
[shouting] I want him dead. you get me?!
Dead! Dead!
Dead!
[sinister music playing]
Any questions?
[dramatic music playing]
-[alarm ringing]
-[cell doors slide open]
[alarm buzzes]
[sighs] I don't get it.
I’ve never sat in the jug this long.
Usually. I get bailed out in a day.
Two. max.
Somebody has you marked.
Who’d you piss off?
You talking to the bulls
when you shouldn’t?
You calling me a snitch?!
I ain’t no snitch. Matches.
Okay. okay. Easy. I’m just saying--
Yeah? Well. don't.
You know what? Drift.
I need to think.
[Matches] Suit yourself.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[struggling. groaning]
-[cracking]
[gun cocks]
[gunshot]
[suspenseful music continues]
[fighting grunts and groans]
[grunts. struggles]
[grunts. pained groan]
[grunts and groans continue]
[suspenseful music swells]
[pained groan]
[grunts. whimpers]
[pained grunt]
[Beckett] Put ‘em both in the hole.
[dramatic music playing]
Matches?
You over there. Matches?
-[Matches] I'm here.
-[sighs]
What you did in the yard...
Thanks.
Thank me by gettin' me a gig
once I'm out of here.
[Dez] Thing is.
Mr. Thorne won’t take just anyone.
You need like a skill.
[Matches]
Bergduff heist in Jersey. Two years back.
-That was you?
-[Matches] I was the wheelman.
Damn.
Big job.
Then they tried to cheat me out of my cut.
Got ugly. But I got my due.
And so did they.
[chuckling]
You sound like this guy I know
from Chicago.
Met him in juvie.
Became bosom buddies.
Got into so much trouble.
He shot up so many joints.
they started calling him “The Riddler."
I got him in with Mr. Thorne.
and now. he's practically runnin' things.
"The Riddler." huh?
That sounds like a guy I need to meet.
[Dez] Can't introduce you if I'm dead.
You said it. Matches.
Sooner or later.
these bastards are gonna get lucky.
-[lock clicks]
-[Matches] You gotta get out of here. Dez.
I'm already working on a plan.
-I figure if we can--
-[door creaks open]
-How the hell...
-I got skills.
-Jeez. you sure do.
-You comin' or not?
[dramatic music playing]
Go!
[suspenseful music playing]
[rapid footsteps]
[pants]
[suspenseful music continues]
[panting. groaning]
[groans. heavy breathing]
-[panting]
-Hurry.
[grunt. groan]
[heavy breathing. pained groan]
[panting. whimpering]
[alarm blaring]
[pained groaning. thud]
[engine revving]
Take that. ya damned screws!
Who’s top of the world now?
Okay. I held up my end.
What about your friends?
Sure. buddy. sure.
A wheelman like you is gonna fit right in.
[dramatic music playing]
Beats the hell out of
those prison monkey-suits.
And they fit.
Thorne controls these warehouses.
Always need some new gear
if a job gets bloody.
And here's Eddie now.
[tense music playing]
[low chuckle]
Eddie!
I was blissfully listening to the radio
when some yutz breaks in
on my favorite program.
talking about an escape from Blackgate.
So I ask myself. who would have the brass
to even try to slide outta Blackgate?
Then it hits me. Dez.
Who else?
I had to blow out of there. Eddie.
Some guys tried to ice me and--
Ice you?
Who in the world would want
to ice you. Dez?
You’re salt of the earth.
We gotta tell Mr. Thorne
people ain’t following the rules.
Yeah. sure.
Thing is. he’s still... on sabbatical.
I’m running things.
Who's this?
Matches. He’s a pal.
Got me outta the jug.
I can vouch for him.
Oh. you can?
Matches. huh?
You some kind of a breakout king. Matches?
Not a king.
-Just a wheelman who’s looking for a--
-[gun cocks]
-[gunshot]
-[groans]
Matches. Stupid name.
You still got good timing. Dez.
Just about to go on a spree.
Eddie’s getting me a new necklace.
Vic took the night off.
and we could use another set of hands.
You in?
Yeah. Eddie. Sure.
You bet.
[dramatic music playing]
[water bubbling]
[dramatic music swells]
Pennyworth. it's me.
I need the car.
[glass breaking]
[suspenseful music playing]
This won't take long.
[kisses]
What's baby in the mood for tonight?
-[suspenseful music swells]
-[glass shattering]
[glass shatters]
-[whooshing. clanging]
-[pained groan]
[glass shatters]
[smoke hissing]
-[whooshing. snaps]
-[gasping]
[fighting grunts and groans]
[grunts]
-[whooshing]
-[pained groan] Dammit!
[grunts]
[suspenseful music continues]
This stinks!
Four times. I try to ice you in the jug.
Four times. you skate!
Eddie?
Then you bust out
with your new tag-along-buddy.
and the Batman just magically
shows up on the spot?
Somebody squealed!
You know what happens to squealers.
don’t you. Dez?
No.
I ain’t no squealer!
Not anymore.
-[rapid gunfire]
-[pained groans]
[grunts]
[car engine starts]
-[tires squeal]
-[Dez groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
[pained breathing]
[dramatic music continues]
[Dez] Matches?
[pained] That you?
[pained chuckle] Of course it is.
You're the Batman.
Funny. huh. [coughing]
Me and Eddie go back so far. but...
turns out my best friend in the world...
was the goddamn Batman.
[long sighs]
[dramatic music continues]
[suspenseful music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
His name is Edward Nygma.
AKA The Riddler.
Impulsive. Reckless. Highly unpredictable.
His kind of chaos can spin out of control.
It pains me to say this.
but your job might become simpler
when Thorne returns to the helm.
At least we know the identity
of the man who has replaced him.
And he’d be behind bars if Matches--
if I hadn’t hesitated.
Some have said that empathy
is the sign of a healthy mind.
Will that be all. sir?
Very good. sir.
[credits music playing]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org